准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
大灰狼海霸王
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
裤头村
我是凯伦  蓝仙女
I'm Karen, the Blue Fairy
今天这个故事特别没品
And this tale lacks class
因为这个故事就叫做
for it's the story of
大灰狼海霸王
"The Big Bad Bubble Bass"
邪恶
Evil
今天好高兴
Rapturous day
我的藏品今天就能集齐了
Today my collection will be completed
终于  猪格伦
At long last, Pigulon
三小猪战队
战猪
仿生猪
预留位
猪格伦大促
仅一天
三小猪神力战队的首领
leader of the Swine Force 3 Action Team
就要到手了
will be mine
得穿什么衣服我都想好了
And I know just what to wear
狼人小子
看好了  狼人小子
Behold, Wolfman Boy
三小猪战队的死对头
mortal enemy of the Swine Force 3
玩具桶
几小时后  故事渐渐发展
Hours later, as the story goes
海霸王整着衣服抵达了目的地
Bubble Bass arrived still adjusting his clothes
猪格伦大促
卖光了
Sold out?
抱歉
Sorry?
不是很想抱歉
Not really?
不可能会有这种事
This can't be happening
没了猪格伦  我的一生就完蛋了
Without Pigulon my life is over
天啊  派大星
Oh, boy, Patrick
不敢相信我们买到最后一个猪格伦了
I can't believe we got the very last Pigulon
对
Yeah
赶快玩玩看
Let's play with him
猪格伦
不能瞎拆猪格伦的宝贝包装
Not Pigulon's precious packaging
一下子就亏成半价了
There goes half his value
挠痒痒可真好用
It's a good scratcher
另一半又亏没了
There goes the other half
实在忍不了了
This cannot stand
必须从那群傻子手中解放猪格伦
I must liberate Pigulon
from the clutches of those buffoons
不好意思  先生们
Pardon me, good sirs
我很难不注意到你们的猪格伦手办
I couldn't help but notice your Pigulon action figure
我能向你们买
Might I buy
换
trade
要不就骗过来吗
or swindle him from you?
归你了  海霸王
He's all yours, Bubble Bass
能为朋友干啥都行
Anything for a friend
等等
Wait
我想玩猪猪人
I wanna play with the pig man
它也是我的
He's mine too
抱歉
Sorry
我都忘了
I forgot
猪格伦是我跟派大星一起出钱买的
Patrick and I both chipped in to buy Pigulon
那就再见了
Welp, see you later
我以宅神的名义
By the gods of nerd-dom
一定要抢到那个猪格伦
I will acquire that Pigulon
无论付出什么代价
No matter what
于是海霸王谋划着  鼓起勇气
So Bubble Bass plotted, his courage he'd found
自顾自地大声咆哮
as he ranted and raved with no one around
给我消失  破铜烂铁
Be gone, vile machine
有玩具等着我去救
I have a toy to rescue
你好  神秘陌生人
Hello, mysterious stranger
要我帮什么忙
How may I help you?
我是玩具检查员
The Toy Inspector
我必须把从你家搜查到的危险玩具
I'll have to take any dangerous toys
found on your premises
带回局里审问
back to the station for questioning
危险玩具
Dangerous toys?
快进来看看
You better come in right away
好  你把你那一点点玩具放哪去了
Yes, now where do you keep
your meager allotment of playthings?
就在保险库里
Over here in the vault
保险库
Vault?
开始检查吧
Let's start, shall we?
有不少玩具都得检查呢
We've got a lot of toys to get through
幸好我按字母顺序都排好了
Luckily, I alphabetized them
这是食蚁兽艾伦
This is Aaron Aardvark
这个危险吗
Is he dangerous?
不危险
No
这是食蚁兽艾比
This is Abbie Aardvark
这个危险吗
Is she dangerous?
不危险
No
这是食蚁兽艾伯
This is Albert Aardvark
这个危险吗
Is he dangerous?
不危险
No
安全得很
It's fine
检查了不少玩具后
现在来检查P
And on to the Ps
这是猪神猪格伦
This is Porktastic Pigulon
这个危险吗
Is he dangerous?
对
Yes
真的非常危
He's very dang--
顺序搞错了
I went out of order
这是高危帕西瓦
This is Perilous Percival
这个危险吗
Is he dangerous?
对  你好
Yes, hello
我是世界知名猎鬼师
I'm a world-famous ghost hunter
我检测到你家出现大规模闹鬼
And I've detected a massive haunting
occurring within your domicile
必须把你家扫描一遍
I'll have to scan your home
找出被附身的物品
to pinpoint the possessed item
鬼魂活动还挺多
Lots of ghost activity
真的吗
There is?
对
Yes
找到了
This is it
这件物品内含恶灵
This item contains a malevolent spirit
不会吧  猪格伦中招了
Oh, no, not Pigulon
必须将其带回实验室
I'll have to take him back to the lab
把恶鬼遏制住
for spectral containment
不必
No need
对  我们马上就在这替你驱鬼
Yeah, we'll banish that ghost for you right here
谁这么大胆  敢把我驱离这个境界
Who dares banish me from this plane?
是他起的头
He started it
不不不
No, no, no
不不
No, no
耶  猪格伦得救了
Yay, Pigulon is saved
害绵宝宝
ScumBob
屁大星
Putrick
你们这群大白痴快把猪格伦交出来
You blithering fools better hand over Pigulon
不然我大喝特喝
or I'll chug, and I'll glug
打嗝把你家吹塌
and I'll belch your house down
没人在家
Nobody's home
来喝大泡弹打嗝燃料
Time for some Fizz Bomb burp fuel
大泡弹
我说  快把猪格伦交出来
I said hand over Pigulon
不然我大喝特喝
or I'll chug, and I'll glug
打嗝把你家吹塌
and I'll belch your house down
第二遍
Again
祝你好运
Good luck
我用石头造的这个石头
I built this rock entirely out of rock
火山辣酱
来加加热吧
Let's turn up the heat
这石头不是按传统方法做的
They just don't make rocks the way they used to
章鱼哥  章鱼哥
Squidward, Squidward
章鱼章鱼
Squid, Squid
放我们进去
Let us in
章鱼章鱼
Squid, Squid
快
Come on
没兴趣
Not interested
没兴趣三个字  你们哪个字听不明白
What part of "not interested" don't you understand?
不好意思  章鱼哥
Pardon me, Squidward
我要在你家取走那个猪格伦娃娃
I'm going to need that Pigulon doll
within your residence
我说了没兴趣
I said not interested
那我大喝特喝
Then I'll chug, and I'll glug
打嗝把你家也一块吹塌
and I'll belch your house down too
大泡弹可乐
给我搞不懂了
I don't understand
打这么多嗝  早该把他家变臭气了
Those burps should have rendered his home
into stinky vapors
抱歉  海霸王
Sorry, Bubble Bass
我给我家做了防海绵宝宝处理
I just had my house SpongeBob-proofed
他的打嗝计划失败了
With his belching now foiled
只剩下一个计划
he had but one plan
跑回家找妈妈  男儿泪轻弹
run home to his mommy and cry like a man
他泪如泉涌  向他妈撒了谎
He wept like a fountain and lied to the ma'am
说那些男生是坏蛋
Those boys were the bullies
而他是他妈的可爱小羊
and he her sweet lamb
他妈暴怒
His mother was livid
她尖叫  她吐唾沫
She screamed, and she spat
绝对不让坏蛋抢她儿子玩具
No villain should take her son's toy like that
我好失望
I am so disappointed
你打嗝早该到高一的水平了
You should be belching at a tenth-grade level by now
让老妈给你示范怎么做
Let Mama show you how it's done
给你  老妈
Here, Mother
那玩意我用不着
I don't need that stuff
你们快把我家海霸王玩具还回去
You boys had better give my Bubble Bass his toy back
可  玩具是我们的
B--but it's our toy
我还有小票
I have the receipt
海霸王
Bubble Bass
老妈  那收据肯定是伪造的
M-M-Mama, th-th-that receipt must be a forgery
不要  老妈
No, Mama
拜托
Please
我只是想
I was just trying to--
别哭了
Don't cry
我们有东西可以让你振作起来
We got something that might cheer you up
真的吗
You do?
我跟派大星要把猪格伦给你
Patrick and I want you to have Pigulon
开心
Joy
给我给我给我
Gimme, gimme, gimme
拿去吧
Here you go
你一定会爱上的
I know you'll love him
我们把玩得特开心
We sure had fun playing with him
海霸王自诩获胜了
Well, Bubble Bass won, so he told himself
他跑回家把他的新娃娃放上了架
as he ran home to put his new doll on the shelf
章鱼哥被迫独自一人重建自己家
Squidward was forced to rebuild alone
他的保险并不赔付
His insurance won't cover
被打嗝吹塌的住房损失
belch damage to home
都是你童话故事害的
Your fairy tale did this
快给我滚
Get outta here
各位再会
Farewell
下次讲故事再见
Until next story time
海底厌绵社
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
动画总监
指导总监
统筹
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
我们玩得可开心了  垃圾
We had some good times, Trashy
不过你一定会爱上垃圾场的
But you're gonna love the dump
还能交到不少垃圾新朋友
You'll make so many trashy new friends
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you
泡芙老师好
Hi, Mrs. Puff
我不在
I'm not here
我的错
My mistake
痞老板好
Hi, Plankton
海霸王好
Hi, Bubble Bass
邮递员先生好
Hi, Mr. Mailman
我们都不在
We're not here
我得戴眼镜了
Maybe I need glasses
海绵受害者同伴们
Fellow sponge sufferers
第413届厌绵社大会
the 431st We Hate SpongeBob Club
现在正式开始
will now come to order
我们的社训是
And now our motto
我们对海绵宝宝没有恶意
We don't mean SpongeBob any harm
只是单纯受不了他
We just can't stand him
谁愿意分享
Does anyone have any
海绵宝宝害你们新吃的苦头
new sponge-pain they would like to share?
你吃了多少次苦头
How much time do you have?
我愿意
I do
我可想分享了
Oh, yes, I do
我一定要拆开装满我苦头的包裹
I have to unwrap my package of pain
分享先慢着
Hold that agony
你好  章鱼哥
Hello, Squidward
继续
Proceed
我有受的苦要分享
I have some misfortune to share
主席有请受害者泡芙发言
The chair recognizes sufferer Puff
请取发言海绵
Please receive the Speaking Sponge
那是上周的事情
It all began last week
当时我还在享受我最爱的事之一
I was enjoying one of my favorite things
给同学颁发驾照
awarding a student their driver's license
滑浪学校
你通过了驾考  贝尔蒂
You've passed your driver's exam, Bertie
裤头村驾照
恭喜你
Congratulations
没了你我肯定考不过  泡芙老师
I couldn't have done it without you, Mrs. Puff
你肯定人人都能教得会
I bet you can teach anyone
几乎算是人人
Almost anyone
驾照不错
Nice license
我能摸摸吗
Can I touch it?
恶心
Gross
看样子你好像有空啊  泡芙老师
Well, looks like you have an opening
in your schedule, Mrs. Puff
我想走
I tried to leave
但大家都知道  没人能逃得掉
but we all know there is no escape from
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
安全加速进入车流
Accelerate safely into traffic
现在来三百六十度回旋
Now for a 360-point turn
停
差点闯停车标志牌了
Almost ran a stop sign
海绵宝宝毁了我美丽的学校
SpongeBob destroyed my beautiful school
就跟上周一个样
Just like last week
没事
It's okay
有我们陪着你
We're here for you
谁想接下去分享的
Who would like to share next?
我想
I would
我想分享抱抱
I'd like to share a hug
看来得让你跺上邮票了
Looks like you could use a stamp
秘鲁收
接下来该轮到我了
I believe that I am next in the roundelay
给我发言海绵
My speaking sponge, please
我本来在蟹堡王
I was at the Krusty Krab
想在第一餐和第二餐间隙吃顿点心
to grab a light snack between first and second lunch
上菜了  尊贵的客人
Order up, oh, valued customer
我饥饿的胃总算有了寄托
Finally sustenance for my starving stomach
希望很完美
I hope it's perfect
不完美
It's not perfect
太油了
It's too greasy
这根薯条也不够油
And this fry isn't greasy enough
不管我想吃什么
Try as I might--
海绵宝宝一点卡路里都不让我摄入
SpongeBob would not let me consume a single calorie
我本来想喝点汽水解解渴
I tried to take a sip of soda to slake my thirst
泡不够多
Not fizzy enough
那个浑身是洞的浑蛋
That perforated pest
就是一口蟹黄堡都不让我吃
wouldn't let me taste a morsel of Krabby Patty
把我蟹黄堡还来  吹毛求疵的臭海绵
Give me back my patty, you festering fusspot
不行
I can't
芝麻排得不整齐
The sesame seeds are misaligned
生菜起了太多皱
and the lettuce has too many wrinkles
番茄失去了光泽
The tomato has lost its sheen
快让我吃东西  可恶的妨碍者
Let me eat, you insufferable interrupter
我赢了
Victory is mine
有点海绵味  不过还行
A tad spongy, but not bad
那个煎炸厨师害我得了
That fry cook has given me a slight case of
消化不良
indigestion
绝不能让客人吃到不完美的蟹黄堡
I shall let no customer eat a less-than-perfect patty
忘戴帽子了
I forgot my hat
那个白痴害我肚脐都打结了
That squishy simpleton left my navel in knots
你这也叫吃尽苦头
You call that suffering?
给你们讲个真正可怕的故事
I'll tell you a truly terrifying tale
那是一个黑夜  海绵四处出没
It was a dark and spongy night
海之霸
我静静在实验室里
I was working peacefully in my lab
研究最新发明来
on my newest invention to, uh
帮助鱼类
help fishkind?
对  就这样
Yeah, that's it
好  我的恐怖厕纸
Yes, my terrible toilet paper
会把裤头村从海底抹去
will wipe Bikini Bottom off the face of the ocean
纸里还加了衬芯
Plus it's quilted
为什么老是有东西害我没法好好奸笑
Why does something always ruin a good evil laugh?
就在那时  我看到了它
But then I saw it
有只野生的海绵宝宝进入了我实验室
A wild SpongeBob had gotten into my lab
凯伦
Karen
它又进来了
It got in again
你窗户又忘关了吗
Did you leave the window open again?
跑进我主机里了
It's in my mainframe
你个坏鸟
You dirty bird
快点下来
Get down from there
坏
Git
快点  懒骨头
Come on, Lazybones
把它扫到门外去
Sweep it out the door
他把我们都锁外面了
He's locked us out
所以要是听到了海绵宝宝的可怕声音
So if you hear that horrible sound of a SpongeBob
马上跑
just run
逃命要紧
Run for your lives
大家淡定
Calm down
我空调又出故障了
My AC is just acting up again
感谢海神王
Thank Neptune
你们这样就吃尽苦头了吗
You think you all have it bad?
等着听我实时发生的海绵恐怖故事吧
Wait until you hear my tale
of spongy terror in real time
三
Three
二
two
一
one
他来了
He had arrived
但是门外却没人
But there was no one there
可能的确无事发生
Perhaps it was nothing
会不会海绵宝宝已经早就进来了
Or was SpongeBob already in the house?
我能借杯盐水吗
Could I borrow a cup of saltwater?
给
Here
当然  盐水只是妄图不请自来的借口
Of course, the saltwater was just a ruse
to come inside uninvited
你们在开派对吗
Are you having a party?
海绵宝宝自然而然地抓紧时间
Naturally, SpongeBob lost no time
把房里所有人都烦一遍
annoying everyone in the room
嗨  泡芙老师
Hi, Mrs. Puff
等不及要上下一节课了
I can't wait until my next lesson
邮递员  不得不说
Mailman, I gotta tell ya
你送来的每一件包裹都是特别快递
every package from you is a special delivery
以后再见  好不好
Let's catch up soon, huh?
样子还挺健康  海霸王
Looking fit, Bubble Bass
最近是不是在举重啊
Been pumping the iron, huh?
还有痞老板  有没有人跟你说过
And, Plankton, has anyone ever told you
你的眼睛最可爱
that you have the loveliest eye?
当然  如果海绵宝宝就在附近
Of course, if SpongeBob was around
那他的粉红尖头朋友也不会远到哪去
his pointy pink pal couldn't be far behind
你家潘趣酒没了
You're out of punch
放心  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
我会再调一批特制菠萝潘趣酒的
I'll mix up a batch of my special pineapple punch
手工家常制作
It's homemade
用我家墙壁做的
Made out of the walls of my home
凡是没有海绵宝宝搞破坏的故事
And no SpongeBob story would be complete
全都是不完整的
without him destroying something
菠萝潘趣酒来了
I've got pineapple punch
讲完了
The end
我们现在得去哪继续开社内大会
Where are we gonna finish our club meeting now?
我知道有地方可以让你们继续开会
I know a place you could have your meeting
谁准备好要吃餐前点心了
Who's ready for hors d'oeuvres?
小心有
Watch out for the--
牙签
Toothpicks
我们发言海绵都用光了
We're all out of speaking sponges
才没用光呢
Oh, no, you're not
还剩一个
There's one left
然后我就
And I was
咳他邮件咳了好几个星期
Coughing up his mail for weeks
我宣布
I declare
本次厌绵社大会
this meeting of the We Hate SpongeBob Club
休会
adjourned